# 你看真好 沙沙的
Look how good this is, how mealy
# 咸蛋黄土豆球
Salted egg yolk potato balls
# 我看这儿摆着几个土豆
I see we have a couple of potatoes here
# 这土豆可好 红的
These are good quality red skin potatoes
# 咱今天做一土豆球
We are making some potato balls today
# 不能浪费 大爷您看 土豆开花了
We shouldn't waste anything. Daye look, the potatoes have cracked open
# 蒸了一个半小时 土豆香味出来喽
We have steamed them for 1.5 hours, and potatoes smell so fragrant
# 大的多蒸会儿 小的少蒸会儿
Make sure to steam the bigger ones for longer and the smaller ones for shorter
# 如果说我们网友着急 想快
If you are in a hurry,
# 我们就	切成片 它更快
Slice the potatoes and then steam
# 有个二十分钟就齐了
You would only need 20mins in that case
# 拿出来有点烫
They are quite hot
# 直接开了花了 大爷您看 特别沙
Look at the crack. Daye, look how mealy they are.
# 这是内蒙的土豆有名
These are the famous Inner Mongolia potatoes
# 沙绵糯香看见没有
Mealy, soft, fragrant and fluffy
# 本来我用这土豆想做一什么你知道么
Do you know what I was planning to make with this?
# 西餐的土豆泥
Western style mashed potatoes
# 用奶油做很简单
It is very simple, just add some cream
# 但是今天魏刚强非得让我做一球儿
But today Gangqiang Wei, Erbai's disciple, made me make some balls
# 师父做球儿吧做球儿吧
"Master, please make some balls"
# 师父现在宁不过徒弟啦
Now the master has to listen to the disciple
# 下手 赶紧动手
Let's get started
# 我先来一块 你先来一块尝尝
Let me try a piece first. - Here you go
# 这土豆太好吃了
This potato is so good
# 刚我吃啊 绵软 特别香 沙沙的
I just had it. It's soft, mealy and super fragrant
# 而且它是糯香
And it is a sticky fragrant
# 这世界的土豆谁家最好
Where is the best potato in the world from?
# 瑞典 他有一小土豆
Sweden. They have these small potatoes
# 我们曾经到那儿旅游 吃个西餐吧
When I was travelling in Sweden and had some local dishes
# 上来两大盘子黄油焗土豆
We were served with two big plates of butter braised potatoes
# 导游说 大爷这个体型顶多吃五个
Our tour guide said "Daye, you can have 5 potatoes max for your size"
# 就跟乒乓球那么大
They were the sizes of ping pong balls
# 我说五个土豆能吃饱了
I was like how can 5 be enough for me?
# 说这个土豆 您在半小时以后才能喝水
And the tour guide continued to tell me to not drink water for the first 30 mins after the meal
# 不然的话这土豆可厉害
Otherwise the potatoes will teach you a lesson
# 我说啊 这土豆肯定吃不饱
I was like how can 5 potatoes be enough for me
# 我吃了五个 等到回屋
I had 5 and went back to my room
# 喝完茶以后 您猜怎么着
And had some tea. Guess what?
# 撑的慌了
I was too full
# 得了 拿刀搓进去了
Let's mash it in with a knife
# 今儿二伯的活都是烫手的活
All Erbai’s work today is meddling with hot ingredients with bare hands
# 下一步该烫澄面了 为了定型儿
Next let's cook some wheat flour for the shape of the balls
# 我来浇开水师父
Master, I will pour in some boiling water
# 二两开水烫一下
2 liang (500g) boiling water to cook it a bit
# 澄面是130克
We have 130g of wheat flour
# 加上土豆 这很烫啊这个
Now add in the potatoes. Be careful it is very hot
# 黄油40克
40g of butter
# 加盐加上底口 没有底味它能好吃吗
Add some salt for the base flavour. It won't taste good with a base flavour.
# 你看大爷 多好看
Look at this Daye. Look how pretty.
# 好看 金黄色
Yea, very pretty and the color is the right gold
# 干澄面再加点
Now add some wheat flour
# 加完烫的澄面再加点干的澄面
We are adding some dry wheat flour after adding some cooked
# 其实最健康的大爷 就是原始的
Daye, actually the healthiest way to eat is just the original
# 蒸完了蘸点酱油一吃
Dip the potatoes in some soy sauce after steaming it
# 小时候的记忆 小时候就撒点盐
Yea I remember when I was little, I used to put a bit of salt on the potatoes
# 咱再接着来点白胡椒粉
Next up let's add some white pepper powder
# 今天这土豆球肯定好吃
I can't wait to taste the potato balls today
# 为了使这土豆泥更加细腻
Let's mash it up a bit with a knife
# 拿刀把它碾一碾
So that it is more smooth
# 二伯是做菜 讲究不将就
Erbai's cooking attends to the details
# 该开剂子了吧师父
Master, should we split it into smaller pieces
# 咸蛋黄馅
Salted egg yolk filling
# 咸蛋黄酱冷冻了有一个小时
We froze the sauce for about an hour
# 如果说有条件的话 冻一夜更好
If you have the time, it is better to freeze overnight
# 蛋黄酱跟咸蛋黄俩合二为一
Let's mix the yolk sauce and the yolk together
# 这是鸭蛋黄 咸鸭蛋蛋黄
This is duck egg yolk. Salted duck egg yolk
# 行了 圆球
Ok, it is round
# 球小装大馅儿
A small ball with lots of filling
# 好土豆球搓好了 下锅了 六成油温
Ok, that is all of the balls. Fry it in oil that is 180C
# 炸上喽
Let's fry!
# 先叫它定型 定完型再推  要不就散了
Don't move things around until the shape has formed. It will fall apart otherwise
# 土豆球出锅喽 好了
Let's take them out of the oil
# 咸蛋黄土豆球
Salted egg yolk potato balls
# 真好 沙沙的
So good, so mealy
# 大爷 我不要那（沾）番茄的
Daye - I don't need ketchup
# 我就要那个（原味的  ）
I like it plain
# 这咸味的也好吃 真好吃
The savoury flavor tastes really good
# 沾上沙司 别有味道
It has a unique flavour with ketchup
# 我说一下这个土豆
I'll say one thing about the potatoes
# 炸出来你看见没有 刚强
Gangqiang, do you see the little pearls on the balls
# 带小珍珠
after frying?
# 有点像咱们炸的珍珠馓子
It's like the pearl Sanzi, fried dough strips, that we fry.
# 这还可以按照粤菜流沙包那种方法
You can also make it like the Cantonese custard buns
# 制个流沙馅
and make a runny yolk filling
# 蛋黄酱这个适合家庭做
The salted yolk sauce is good for home cooking
# 不复杂 简化了
It simplifies the process
# 有网友说 听说这次
Some of our followers heard that
# 大爷二伯去延吉了
Daye and Erbai went to Yanji
# 然后想顺便问问
And wanted to ask
# 朝鲜泡菜和四川泡菜
The difference between North Korean style kimchi and Sichuan pickled vegetables - these are both called “Pao Cai” in Chinese, hence the confusion
# 各自的特点
There unique features
# 及腌制方法
And how to cure them
# 这两种口味
These two pickles
# 在腌制的方法上
are similar
# 比较相同
in terms of curing methods
# 但是口味有所不同
But the flavours are quite different
# 当我们两国进行交流的时候
When we met up for cultural exchange
# 我们也曾经让他们给我们做过
They demonstrated how to make
# 朝鲜泡菜
North Korean style kimchi
# 山东寿光地区
In Shouguang, Shandong area
# 专门为朝鲜和韩国种的大白菜
They grow napa cabbages for North and South Korea
# 那一颗白菜能达到15斤
One napa cabbage can weigh up to 15 Jin, 7.5 kg
# 含水量也高 很脆
Those cabbages have a high water content and are very crunchy
# 用生菜经过外边的清洗 摘
After washing the cabbage from the outside
# 有的时候一开两半
Sometimes splitting in half
# 有的还开成条
Or split it into strips
# 但是它是整颗的 先杀盐
But it is still a whole head of cabbage and cure it with salt
# 有的搁辣椒糊 把它拌起来
Sometimes also mix it with pepper flakes slurry
# 杀完水以后
After getting the excess water out
# 放辣椒面
Put in the red pepper flakes
# 一层一层摆在缸里面
Layer the cabbages in a pot
# 还放白酒
And then put in some Baijiu
# 对 为了增加一些口味
Yea for some extra flavours
# 还有的放点梨
Some people also put pears
# 放点苹果
and apples
# 为了好看 （放）我们北京
Sometimes even the red centered radishes
# 芯儿里面萝卜
from Beijing
# 为了发酵的更加充分
For it to cure more thoroughly
# 切一点儿鱼丝码在缸的浮面上
Cut up some fish slices on the top of the pot
# 里边还要放韭菜
And add some chives
# 压着一个大石头
Then put a big rock on the top
# 第二天还要倒一下缸
You also have to mix things up in the pot the second day
# 倒两三次
Mix for two to three times
# 大约在十天
The kimchi is ready in 10
# 到十二天 这个白菜就发酵好了
to 12 days
# 大爷说的详细吗
Is Daye giving you enough details?
# 详细 为什么知道吗 您说
Yea, super detailed. - Do you know why?
# 大爷是泡菜协会的副会长
Daye is the associate chair of the Pickled Vegetable Association
# 真的
Really?
# 朝鲜泡菜口味有什么特点
What are the flavours of the North Korean style kimchi?
# 辣 脆 咸 酸
Spicy, crunch, savory and sour
# 我跟二伯去延边
When I went to Yanbian with Erbai
# 我们品尝的泡菜
The kimchi we tastes
# 基本上以咸为主
Was mostly savory
# 酸味不大
Wasn't too sour
# 辣味也不是很冲
The spiciness wasn't too overpowering
# 我参加了一个
I also attended
# 韩国泡菜的一个推介会
A South Korean kimchi conference
# 什么都没有
Kimchi was a must
# 必须有泡菜
even if nothing else is available
# 用泡菜炒五花肉 烤五花肉
Kimchi fried pork belly, BBQ pork belly
# 烤泡菜
BBQ kimchi
# 然后带着泡菜卷着吃
And make it into a kimchi wrap
# 还有炒年糕
Also tteokbokki
# 用泡菜煮年糕
Use kimchi to cook the rice cakes
# 加上什么知道吗
Do you know what else you can add?
# 芝士 不是 加上方便面可好吃了
Cheese? - No, it tastes so good with ramen
# 做汤 部队火锅
You can also make soup, Budae Jjigae
# 韩国的泡菜
The kimchi from South Korean
# 跟朝鲜泡菜有相同之处
Shares some flavours with the North Korean style
# 口味以咸 酸
The flavours are savory and sour
# 但是他不放生鱼
But they don't use raw fish
# 有的放小鱼干儿
They use dried fish
# 也是属于发酵的一种方法
Which is also a way to cure
# 总的讲这是南北差异
It is the difference between the south and the north
# 北朝鲜基本上
In North Korea,
# 泡菜是不离饭桌的
the kimchi doesn't leave the dining table
# 韩国把泡菜当家庭就餐的
In South Korea, kimchi is a necessity for
# 必需品
eating at home
# 剩下来我再说说四川泡菜
Next up, let's talk about Sichuan style pickled vegetables
# 应该说无所不可泡
Basically you can pickle anything you want
# 都可以泡
Anything
# 像我们的豇豆啊 莴笋啊
Vegetables like cowpeas, asparagus lettuce
# 黄瓜萝卜所有的东西都可以泡
Cucumbers, daikon, anything you want
# 四川泡菜也很讲究
THe key to Sichuan pickles is
# 都是用井水纯净水
purified water from wells
# 还有 他自贡的盐
And salt from Zigong
# 实际上泡菜和我们北京这个地区
The process of making pickled vegetables
# 就跟我们腌菜
is very similar to
# 基本相同
how we cure vegetables in Beijing
# 只不过盐的控制是很重要的
You have to control how much salt that goes in
# 在制汤的时候
When making the pickling juice
# 就要用熟水
You have to use boiled water
# 放上花椒
Add some peppercorns
# 花椒是防腐的
Peppercorns act as a preservative
# 放上干辣椒
Add some dried chilis
# 提高它的辣味
To make it a bit more spicy
# 还有姜还有蒜
And add some ginger and garlic
# 然后还要有白酒
And Baijiu
# 还要放一些红糖
some brown sugar
# 这几样原料起什么作用
Why are we adding these ingredients?
# 比如说我们腌这个泡菜
For example, when we are curing the vegetables,
# 稍微起了点白膜
There is a white film at the top
# 倒上点白酒
We can add some Baijiu
# 加点红糖
and brown sugar
# 第二天这白膜就消失了
The film will disappear the next day
# 防腐的作用
They are both preservatives
# 最关键点是把所有的菜
Also the most important point
# 一定要把这个水分全部控干
is to remove any water on the vegetables
# 然后杀盐
and cure it with salt
# 十斤菜在六两到七两盐
For 10 jin, 5kg, vegetables, use 6-7 liang, 300-350g, salt
# 杀盐占一部分 杀完盐以后
Curing with salt is also a part of remove water
# 装到一个特定的泡菜坛子里头
Then put the vegetables into designated pots.
# 大家看到 上面扣一碗
The pots we are familiar with always have a flipped bowl at the top
# 外边有个沿
and a rim around it
# 是吧
right?
# 装到里边以后
After putting the vegetables in
# 把熬好的泡菜水
Put the cooled pickling water in
# 晾凉了以后放在里边
# 头两天要倒坛
Mix things up a bit for the first two days
# 然后把这个碗扣在盘子上
And then flip the bowl onto the pot
# 四周浇上水
Pour water in the rim
# 放到阴凉地
And put the pot in the shade
# 经过十天到十五天的发酵
The pickle is ready in
# 这个泡菜就可以吃了
10 to 15 days
# 有辣味
It is spicy,
# 有麻味
numbing,
# 酸 咸 脆 爽
sour, savoury, crunchy and refreshing
# 用四川泡菜
You can make many dishes
# 也能做很多菜
With Sichuan pickles
# 在巴蜀之地饮食当中的必需品
It is a necessity in Bashu Cuisine
# 明白了
Got it
# 让二伯说两句呗
Anything to add Erbai?
# 那刚才说的这些（算）三种泡菜
The pickles you mentioned count as 3 types
# 就补充一句
Just one more thing to add
# 大爷讲的非常详细了
Daye's description is already very detailed
# 比如大爷说倒缸
For example, mixing things in the pot
# 倒缸的时候
When you are doing it
# 你一定带好手套
Make sure to wear gloves
# 千万别着油
And not let any oil in
# 腌好时候 你吃的时候
After it is ready, when you are eating
# 一定要用干净的筷子去夹
Pick the pickles with clean chopsticks
# 就是封口的时候
When you are sealing the pot
# 那水一定要封严
Make sure the water seals the pot completely